Mariana Greenway Flat 2, Hillview Court, Hillview Road, Hilltown, HZ4 8CV greenwaym@jm.ac.uk 07877009008

A registered nutrition professional with a solid research background, industry experience and a teaching portfolio. I am interested in developing a career which combines teaching and research, while maintaining my interest in public engagement with nutrition and the wider STEM field.

Education

Liverpool John Moores University (2020-2023)

PhD

NHS/LJMU funded research titled 'The role of parents and schools in the nutritional choices made by children aged 10-14' (Abstract in Appendix 1). Joint supervisors: Professor Alison LaMotte, Department of Nutrition and Food, LJMU and Dr Henling Strauss, Professor of Paediatrics, Chester University Hospital.

University of Nottingham (2017-2020)

BSc Nutrition and Food Science

Modules included nutrition and the health of populations, trends in food research and nutrition, metabolism and disease. Final-year project on 'Food flavourings - physical and psychological effects on children' based on research carried out through a Nutrition Society Summer Studentship.

Notts County High School (2010-2017)

A-levels: chemistry, biology, geography. AS-level maths.

8 GCSEs including English language and English literature.

Teaching/supervising experience

Teaching assistant, Liverpool John Moores University (2021-present)

- Supervising undergraduate dissertations
- Assisting with programme development and student assessment
- Delivering teaching sessions on BSc Nutrition and Nutrition and Public Health
- Student assessment

Guest lecturer, BSc Nutrition and Food Science, University of Nottingham (2020)

- Delivered five lectures by invitation
- Supervised and assessed student presentations

Summer school lecturer, Liverpool John Moores University (2020-2021)

- Coordinating summer school programme
- · Devising and delivering interactive teaching sessions

Publications

- Greenway M, Neill L, Smith J 'Apple or Biscuit: Children's food choices' (2022) Journal of Child Nutrition 20:934-939
- Greenway M, Neill L, Smith J 'Mum, can I have something to eat: parents' role in children's eating patterns' Journal of Child Nutrition (2021) 16:723-728
- Partrillo, V, Greenway M, 'How can schools help children with their food choices?' Primary Education (2020) 25:1029-1032

Research skills

- Taking and interpreting food diaries
- Qualitative interviewing
- Analysis using XJP and PSS 2.0 industry standard systems
- Mathematical modelling
- Application of scientific theory to qualitative data

Conferences and presentations

- British Nutrition Foundation Child Health Conference 2023 Workshop on 'The influence of parents in children's food choices'
- Big Bang 2022 Professional Strand presentation on STEM Ambassadors
- Association for Nutrition NW Branch Conference 2022 Paper on 'Working with parents'
- Chester University Hospital Child Nutrition Symposium 2021 'How and why do children choose what they eat?'
- Association for Nutrition Annual Student Conference 2020 Workshop on 'Creating a farmers market'
- Association for Nutrition Annual Student Conference 2019 Poster session on child nutrition group work
- Association for Nutrition Annual Student Conference 2018 presentation on 'Parents' role in children's food choices: initial research findings'
- Association for Nutrition NW Branch Conference 2017 Workshop on 'Do farmers markets and food banks share common ground?'

Awards

- Nutrition Society Student Award 2020 for BSc final-year dissertation
- Nutrition Society Summer Studentship 2019

Professional associations

- Registered Associate Nutritionist (ANutr), working towards Registered Nutritionist (RNutr)
- Nutrition Society Student Member and member of Student Council

Other qualifications

- Levels 3 Award in PTLLS Preparing to Teach in the Lifelong Learning Sector
- Level 4 Certificate in Education and Training

Employment

Project assistant, The Food Project, Liverpool (2021-present)

- Devising workshops for parents and young people
- Delivering workshops in schools, Children's Centres, NHS clinics, etc.
- Research to support projects and funding bids
- Supervising placement students

Nutrition adviser, Food Company Ltd, Merseyside (2020-2021)

- Advising product developers on nutritional content of new products
- Quality control of food labelling
- Research to support product development
- Supervising lab staff

Founder member, Dock Street Farmers Market (2017-2020)

- Collaborating with others to create monthly market events
- Coordinating market days
- Negotiating with venues and traders
- Bidding for funding

Trustee, Dock Street Farmers Market (2017-present)

- Strategic direction for the organisation
- Nutritional adviser to the Board
- Coordinating funding bids

STEM ambassador (2016-2017)

• Speaking at STEM events in schools and colleges to engage young people

Volunteer nutrition assistant, NHS Nottingham (2015-2017)

- Working under the direction of a community dietitian to help parents of young children create nutritious meals
- Leading cookery sessions for parents and children